## Sireesha P

Developer, Team Lead, System Analyst, Agile Badge

#### Contact

#### **Address**

Hyderabad, 500090

#### **Phone**

703-200-0382

#### E-mail

sireeshapurushotham@gmail .com

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sireeshapurushotham/

#### **WWW**

https://github.com/sireeshap

#### **Skills**

Bootstrap 3, 4, 5

Upper intermediate

Angular 1, 2, 4, 5, 6, 8, 10, 11, 12

Upper intermediate

Micro front ends

CSS, SCSS, SASS

Upper intermediate

React JS, Redux

Intermediate

UI/UX

#### Experience: 11.6 years

Solution-driven professional excelling in highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions to challenges and focused on customer satisfaction. As a MEAN stack Developer proven experience developing consumer-focused web sites using HTML, CSS, JQuery, Angular and Micro front ends, Node js, MySQL, NoSQL, React, NextJs. Hands on exposure on JAVA, Microsoft Azure, AWS S3 bucket, DOCKER, GCP, Workbench, Microsoft SQL server management. Experience building products for desktop, phone and mobile app users, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices, usability and speed. Responding to challenges by designing and developing solutions and building web applications aligned to customer's services. Translating solutions into code and working across many different APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

## **Work History**

2022-01 -Current

## Senior System Analyst

IBM, Hyderabad

- Currently Working on "London Stack Exchange
   Application" for BetaNxt. Helping them to restructure
   the legacy application.
- Design customized development frameworks for customers based on specific business goals and budgetary constraints.
- Worked closely with Ausnet (Australia) services & PitneyBows (USA) clients as MEAN stack developer (Micro front end architecture)
- Identified areas that could be improved through specific processes and addition of new software.
- Leading Juniors, Code Review & Code deliverables sprint wise.
- Created all requirements flows and distributed it to team members and key stakeholders.(Smart Access Management project-kiosk integration)
- Escalated project-related issues quickly to help rectify problems and avoid delays.
- Developed and implemented workflow templates, prioritizing efficiency and ease-of-use for end-users of clients.
- Test driven Development using Jasmin & Karma

Upper intermediate

HTML5

Upper intermediate

Node Js, MongoDB, SQL DB

Upper intermediate

Angular material

Intermediate

Ngb Bootsrap

Intermediate

Firebase Deployment

Intermediate

Troubleshooting and debugging

Upper intermediate

Code review & deployments

Intermediate

Performance & Optimization

Intermediate

Javascript, Typescript

Upper intermediate

RXJS, Redux

Intermediate

MongoDB, Mongo Atlas

Upper intermediate

Microsoft MSAL

Intermediate

Power BI Integration

Intermediate

JAVA Bug Fixing

#### framework.

 Worked closely with business users and business analysts to understand functionality and propose creative solutions to meet business needs.

#### 2020-08 -2021-12

## Senior Software Engineer

Biztechsolinc(IBM Vendor), Hyderabad

- Worked as Consultant of IBM and client is western power which is one of Power distribution giant in australia. Working for them to enhance their internal processes. Worked along with WesternPower technologies(Australia) Onshore & offshore team together. handling Front end requirements as well as MSAL integration, Power Bi Integration, Jasmine unit tes cases & backend bug fixing.
- In previous worked with one of the giant in pharmacy industry Bio-rad (USA). Contributed whole UX & UI of an internal application of Bio-rad. All of work includes with Remote team and handling application front end development part which includes Angular 10+, typescript, scss, Bootstrap and other front end libraries.
- Trained and mentored junior developers and engineers, teaching skills in Front end technologies, Agile processes and working to improve overall team performance.

#### 2018-11 -2020-07

## Team Lead Developer

Dreamcaster, Hyderabad

Dreamcaster Pvt Itd is media & travel felids based company which provides platforms to automate booking process for booking operators, travel agencies, publicity cum advertising. Since it involves lot of internal tricky features, got chance to work with major real time services. Here i worked on Angular 8, and React, redux technologies.

https://dreamcaster.in

https://dreamcastervacations.com

https://www.dreamcastertours.com

https://dreamcasterstravel.com

 Distributed individual assignments to team members and monitored progress against production Intermediate

PL/SQL procedure Bug fixing

Elementary

Jasmin Unit test cases

Intermediate

Mixpanel, Analytics services

Intermediate

Microsoft SQL server management

Intermediate

MySQL workbench

Intermediate

SourceTree, GitHub Desktop

Intermediate

Git Commands, GitLab, GitHub

Upper intermediate

Azure, AWS

Intermediate

Next Js

Upper intermediate

Mentoring

Upper intermediate

timetables.

- Took on additional job duties, including Bug fixing and UI designing during unexpected backlog, resulting in meeting project target date.
- Here as part of Internal system development, working on front end React web based components.
- Mentored new members by relaying information on company procedures, coding guidelines and job tasks.
- Delivering complete front end application
- Ensuring high performance on mobile and desktop
- Collaborated with cross-functional development team members to analyze potential system solutions based on evolving client requirements.
- Conducted regression testing, analyzed results and submitted observations to development team.
- Collaborated with business unit team members to design new applications system to enhance client requirements for mobile computing capabilities.
- Orchestrated efficient large-scale software deployments, including testing features and reviewing code.

# 2018-06 - UI/UX Consultant-Angular, 2018-11 Bootstrap(Remote)

Tallyfy, Greater St. Louis Area

Worked as part-time developer for this project and handling Feature development, bug fixing. Had good cooperative Remote working team around the world, required to connect with different time zone people to make things to get work.

- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement.
- Delivering complete front end application
- Writing tested, idiomatic, and documented Angular programs.
- Coordinating the workflow between the UI designer, HTML coder, and myself.
- Cooperating with the back-end developer in the process of building the RESTful API
- Communicating with external web services & API

integration.

- Identify and troubleshoot various website issues and coding problems.
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs.
- Participate in regular sprint planning sessions.
- Participate in code reviews.
- Participate in functional testing of code.

#### 2018-04 -2018-05

## MEAN Stack Developer(Remote)

Hubsell, Berlin Area

HubSell is an automated outbound leads and opportunity generation platform for the B2B industry.

- In this product worked on very new enhancements and new pages in MEAN stack environment.
- Since it is a very small team it gave chance to work on both Backend Service generation, Front end application development along with database operations.
- Here worked as MEAN stack(Mongo DB, Express, Angular JS, Node js) along with Bootstrap and Sass, Gulp.
- Creating API services using NodeJs
- Writing Queries according to business logic and fetch data from MongoDB.
- Creating webpages as per requirements using Angular, Bootstrap and Material design.

#### 2016-12 -2018-03

## Senior UI Developer

Levadata - CMS & RFQ, Hyderabad
LevaData helps global enterprises to improve gross
margins by reducing supply chain costs. In this project, i
worked as a Senior UI developer. I am part of this
product from scratch and became part of the core
team at end. So I got the chance to develop solutions
that can automate the process of Commodity
manager's daily manual work

- Conceived and built optimized landing pages in HTML and CSS, including AgGrid, HighCharts integration and cross-browser compatibility, to support marketing.
- Worked with Angular1, Angular 2, Angular 4 & 5,
   Bootstrap, Scss, Sass along with Jasmin, Karma, NPM,

- Gulp along with Angular material.
- Integrated APIs from the swagger environment,
   Deployment process in Remote AWS.
- Deep knowledge of AngularJS practices and commonly used modules based on extensive work experience
- Creating self-contained, reusable, and testable modules and components
- Validating user actions on the client-side and providing responsive feedback
- Writing non-blocking code, and resorting to advanced techniques such as multi-threading, when needed
- Creating custom, general use modules, and components which extend the elements and modules of core AngularJS

#### 2015-06 -2016-11

## **UI Developer for Microsoft**

People Tech Group, Hyderabad

I worked on Two major projects with major clients. Since both applications are in-house purposes, not able to provide images. But can find details below about products, clients along with my responsibilities.

Client: Microsoft Corporation

- Business Analysis of requirements specified in Wireframes.
- Development of dynamic web application pages as per wireframe's functionality.
- Implementing Bootsrap pages which supportive to angular libraries.
- Coordination with remote UX team to attain application page as per mockup.
- Fallowing Agile methodology & scrum calls on daily basis.
- Resolving of issues in application & maintenance.
- Resource information collection required for page development & coding it using angular JS in Bootstrap pages.
- Participation in Bug Bash & resolving issues on priority basis.

Working with Microsoft VSO version control system & One Note & visual Studio 15.

• Working on Accessibility part of web pages.

#### 2012-02 -2015-05

#### **Software Engineer**

Foursoft IT Solutions, Hyderabad

- Worked as Developer for AyushCare front-end & back-end Management system.
- Development of websites & web applications based on customer requirement using JAVA based technology using the GWT platform.
- Web site development using Bootstrap, CSS, Java script., Angular JS, JQuery &GWT.
- Maintaining communication with clients to know their requirements & has to suggest solution for them.
- Acted as active participant in the implementation of "Reporting Portal" tool.
- Conducted regression testing, analyzed results and submitted observations to development team.

#### **Education**

| 2009-06 - | Master of Science: Computer Science And |
|-----------|---|
| 2011-06   | Engineering                             |

Anna University - Chennai

2005-06 - Bachelor of Science: Information Technology

Sree Vidyanikethan Autonomous Enginnering College -Tirupati

## **Accomplishments**

- IBM Consulting way
- IBM Garage Essentials
- IBM Garage Foundation
- IBM Tech talk session on Micro front ends
- Digital transformation certificate by ISB
- "Pat on Back" award in People Tech

## **Interests**

Articles

Travel